export const chapter = "Chapter - 9: Forests and Wildlife  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the primary function of forests?",
        optionA: "Providing fuel for industrial use",
        optionB: "Preserving physical features of the planet",
        optionC: "Serving as a habitat for humans",
        correctAnswer: "Preserving physical features of the planet",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which type of forest remains green throughout the year and does not shed all its leaves in a particular season?",
        optionA: "Deciduous Forests",
        optionB: "Coniferous Forests",
        optionC: "Evergreen Tropical Forests",
        correctAnswer: "Evergreen Tropical Forests",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which type of forest is found in areas with scanty rainfall and contains trees and plants with thick bark and long roots?",
        optionA: "Deciduous Forests",
        optionB: "Thorny Forests",
        optionC: "Coniferous Forests",
        correctAnswer: "Thorny Forests",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What type of trees grow in cold climates, have needle-like leaves, and bear cones instead of flowers and fruits?",
        optionA: "Deciduous trees",
        optionB: "Conifer trees",
        optionC: "Evergreen trees",
        correctAnswer: "Conifer trees",
      },
      {
        question: "Where are Mangrove Forests typically found in India?",
        optionA: "In the hilly regions of the Himalayas",
        optionB: "In the deltas of major rivers",
        optionC: "In the Western Ghats",
        correctAnswer: "In the deltas of major rivers",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What program encourages every child to plant a tree and take care of it?",
        optionA: "Chipko Movement",
        optionB: "Tree for Every Child",
        optionC: "Vana Mahotsav",
        correctAnswer: "Tree for Every Child",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How many national parks and wildlife sanctuaries are there in India, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "96 national parks and 492 wildlife sanctuaries",
        optionB: "50 national parks and 200 wildlife sanctuaries",
        optionC: "100 national parks and 400 wildlife sanctuaries",
        correctAnswer: "96 national parks and 492 wildlife sanctuaries",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why are wild animals facing the danger of extinction, according to the text?",
        optionA: "Climate change",
        optionB: "Reckless hunting, poaching, and deforestation",
        optionC: "Overpopulation of humans",
        correctAnswer: "Reckless hunting, poaching, and deforestation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which government schemes are mentioned in the text for the development and conservation of forest areas?",
        optionA: "National Mission for a Green India",
        optionB: "National Wildlife Protection Program",
        optionC: "National Animal Preservation Initiative",
        correctAnswer: "National Mission for a Green India",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What type of forests are found in the Western Ghats in Kerala, Karnataka, Maharashtra, and Tamil Nadu?",
        optionA: "Deciduous Forests",
        optionB: "Coniferous Forests",
        optionC: "Evergreen Tropical Forests",
        correctAnswer: "Evergreen Tropical Forests",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Forests are an intricate ecosystem on the earth which contain trees, shrubs, grasses, and more. The constituents of forests, which are _______ and _______, form a major part of the forests.",
        optionA: "Leaves, animals",
        optionB: "Trees, plants",
        optionC: "Rocks, rivers",
        correctAnswer: "Trees, plants",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Forest fulfill all our needs of timber, fuel, fodder, bamboos, and more. They also give us a variety of products that hold great _______ as well as industrial value.",
        optionA: "Cultural",
        optionB: "Financial",
        optionC: "Environmental",
        correctAnswer: "Financial",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Moreover, forests are largely responsible for preserving the physical features of our planet. They monitor soil _______ and prevent it from happening.",
        optionA: "Growth",
        optionB: "Erosion",
        optionC: "Pollution",
        correctAnswer: "Erosion",
      },
      {
        question:
          "There is a great variety in the climate and physical features of India, which is a major reason to have different types of _______ in the country.",
        optionA: "Oceans",
        optionB: "Deserts",
        optionC: "Forests",
        correctAnswer: "Forests",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The areas which have heavy rainfall and hot climate are called tropical, and the trees which remain in leaf throughout the year are called _______. So the forests found in tropical regions with evergreen trees are known as evergreen tropical forests.",
        optionA: "Deciduous trees",
        optionB: "Evergreen trees",
        optionC: "Coniferous trees",
        correctAnswer: "Evergreen trees",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Coniferous trees grow at a height of _______ meters or above in the Himalayan and in the Nilgiri Hills in the South.",
        optionA: "1000",
        optionB: "1600",
        optionC: "2000",
        correctAnswer: "1600",
      },
      {
        question:
          "On the deltas of big rivers, silt is deposited by the rivers or the tidal waves of the ocean. Such places become marshy. This encourages the growth of dense _______.",
        optionA: "Deserts",
        optionB: "Jungles",
        optionC: "Forests",
        correctAnswer: "Forests",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Government of India has started many programs and also passed many laws for the conservation of _______.",
        optionA: "Animals",
        optionB: "Rivers",
        optionC: "Forests",
        correctAnswer: "Forests",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India is blessed with a wide variety of wildlife comprising animals, birds, insects, fishes, and _______.",
        optionA: "Mountains",
        optionB: "Rivers",
        optionC: "Reptiles",
        correctAnswer: "Reptiles",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has established national parks, wildlife sanctuaries, and bird sanctuaries to protect _______.",
        optionA: "Cities",
        optionB: "Lakes",
        optionC: "Wildlife",
        correctAnswer: "Wildlife",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Mumbai is the most populous city in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Mumbai is the capital of the Indian state of Gujarat.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Mumbai is located on the east coast of India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Mumbai is known as the cultural capital of India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Mumbai is situated on the Arabian Sea coast.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Mumbai has a tropical climate with distinct seasons.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Gateway of India is the most important landmark in Mumbai.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Mumbai is the political capital of India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Mumbai is the richest city in India in terms of GDP.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Mumbai is well-connected with other parts of India through an extensive public transport system.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
